Daniel Freitas Ferreira

Address: Marine Rd- Pavilions Apartments -Apartment 52, Dun Laoghaire Email: dan10ff@gmail.com Mobile: 083 3939130

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE A person focused on work where he always works to achieve the maintenance rates proposed by the company. I started my professional career in 2004 at the company GE Transportation as a maintenance planning technician. Since then I worked for several companies, always working in the maintenance sector, working so that all maintenance standards were executed in the best possible way. Over time I acquired leadership roles where I was able to develop my skills. I also worked in the health and safety sector.

KEY COMPETENCIES

- · Relationship Builder
- Team Player
- Administration Skills
- Personal Monitoring
- · Leadership self motivated

WORK EXPERIENCE:

WORK EXPERIENCE:

May 2019 - Currently: Pownall and Hampson Ireland Limited: Dublin

Job Title: Production Supervisor

- Managed and supervised the daily operations of a production team of 20 people.
- Ensured production goals were met through efficient use of resources and adherence to quality standards.
- Implemented and maintained a safe work environment for all employees.
- Developed and executed strategies to increase production efficiency.
- Trained and mentored new employees.

May 2014 — March 2019 ArcelorMittal Mineração Serro Azul

Position: Maintenance planning and control technician

Main achievements:

- Schedule of activities to comply with the maintenance plan.
- · Manage labor to carry out activities
- Planning major shutdowns to renovate equipment;
- Guarantee all the necessary resources to carry out all maintenance activities;
- Control of expenses in the maintenance sector.
- · Issuance of reports with all maintenance indicators;
- Provide training and instructions
- · Control of service contracts for maintenance.

January 2012- June 2013 - White Martins Gases Industriais.

Position: Maintenance planning and control technician

Main achievements:

- Schedule of activities to comply with the maintenance plan.
- Manage labor to carry out activities
- Planning major shutdowns for retrofitting equipment;
- Guarantee all the necessary resources to carry out all maintenance activities;
- Control of expenses in the maintenance sector.

- Issuance of reports with all maintenance indicators;
- Provide training on new work methodologies and presentation of new equipment.

September 2010 - January 2012 - Morson International (Working at VIVO Minas)

Position: Telecommunications Analyst

Main achievements:

- · Equipment failure monitoring and diagnosis;
- Conducting alarm tests via the Supervisory system
- Control of faults presented by the equipment.

January 2009 - December 2009 - Alsco Toalheiro Brasil

Position: Electronic Technician

Main achievements:

- · Corrective and preventive maintenance on electrical equipment;
- Maintenance on Siemens and Alfa PLCs and frequency inverters:
- · Equipment installation;

February 2007 - January 2009 - GE Transportation - GEVISA

Position: Maintenance Planning Technician

Main achievements:

- · Corrective and preventive maintenance planning;
- · Monitoring of the activities performed;
- Development of new suppliers;
- · Supervision of service providers for maintenance;
- Critical view of the process;
- Control of machine availability;
- Work focused on Energy efficiency;
- · Lean Manufacturing;
- Analysis of the time between failures;
- Constant performance in the health and safety sector;
- Creation of lock out tag out procedures;

04/2005 - 01/2007 - Magnesita Service

Position: Technical assistant

Main achievements:

- · Corrective and preventive maintenance planning;
- · Control of materials:
- Supplier developments;
- · Analysis of purchase needs;

EDUCATION

University Graduate in Electronic Engineering and Telecommunication.

PUC - MG (Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais)

Conclusion: 2008

Electronics and Telecommunications Technician

PIO XII School Conclusion: 2002.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Training Courses -

NR-10 course; (Brazilian Standard for Electrical Installations);

- · Lean Manufacturing;
- Power block for equipment maintenance;
 CREA No. 1410391140 (Registration with the engineering council);

Languages: English and native Portuguese;

Computer Skills: SAP, Oracle,